Alec Soth: So about 10 years ago, I got a call from a woman in Texas,
منذ عشر سنوات خلت، تلقيت مكالمة من سيدة تقطن ولاية تكساس،
Stacey Baker,
تدعى ستاسي بيكر،
and she'd seen some of my photographs in an art exhibition
كانت قد شاهدت بعضا من صوري في معرض فني
and was wondering if she could commission me to take a portrait of her parents.
وكانت تتسائل إن كان بإمكاني إلتقاط صورة لوالديها.
Now, at the time I hadn't met Stacey, and I thought this was some sort of
حينها لم أكن قد قابلتها واعتقدت أنهم
wealthy oil tycoon and I'd struck it rich,
من ملوك النفط وأن ثروة ستنزل عليّ
but it was only later that I found out
لكني اكتشفت لاحقاً
she'd actually taken out a loan to make this happen.
أنها في الواقع حصلت على قرض من أجل تحقيق ذلك.
I took the picture of her parents,
قمت بإلتقاط صورة لوالديها،
but I was actually more excited about photographing Stacey.
لكن في الواقع كنت متحمساً لالتقاط صورة لستايسي.
The picture I made that day
الصورة التي التقطها ذلك اليوم
ended up becoming one of my best-known portraits.
أصبحت واحدة من صوري الأكثر شهرة.
At the time I made this picture, Stacey was working as an attorney
حين التقطت هذه الصورة كانت ستايسي تعمل كمدعي عام
for the State of Texas.
في ولاية تكساس.
Not long after, she left her job to study photography in Maine,
بعد مدة قصيرة، استقالت من عملها لدراسة التصوير في ولاية ماين،
and while she was there, she ended up meeting
وأثناء وجودها هناك إنتهى بها الأمر بمقابلة
the director of photography at the New York Times Magazine
مدير التصوير بمجلة نيويورك تايمز
and was actually offered a job.
وفي الواقع قام بعرض وظيفة عليها.
Stacey Baker: In the years since, Alec and I have done
ستاسي بيكر: ومنذ ذلك الوقت قمت أنا وأليك
a number of magazine projects together,
بانجاز عدد من المشاريع معا لصالح المجلة
and we've become friends.
وأصبحنا أصدقاء.
A few months ago, I started talking to Alec about a fascination of mine.
منذ عدة اشهر، تحدثت إلى أليس حول شغف يتملكني.
I've always been obsessed with how couples meet.
كنت دوماً مهووسة بالطريقة التي يلتقي بها الازواج.
I asked Alec how he and his wife Rachel met,
سألت أليك كيف التقى بزوجته راشيل،
and he told me the story of a high school football game
فاخبرني قصة مباراة كرة القدم في الثانوية
where she was 16 and he was 15,
حين كانت هي في السادسة عشرة وهو في الخامسة عشرة،
and he asked her out.
وطلب منها الخروج معه.
He liked her purple hair.
لقد احب لون شعرها الأرجواني
She said yes, and that was it.
وقد وافقت وهكذا كانت القصة.
I then asked Alec if he'd be interested in doing a photography project
بعدها سـألت أليك اذا ما كان مهتماً ببدء مشروع تصوير
exploring this question.
لمعرفة المزيد عن هذا الموضوع.
AS: And I was interested in the question, but I was actually much more interested
اليك: كنت مهتماً بالموضوع بالفعل
in Stacey's motivation for asking it,
لكن اهتمامي بمعرفة دافع ستاسي كان أكبر،
particularly since I'd never known Stacey to have a boyfriend.
ولأننى أعرف أن ستاسي ليس لديها حبيب.
So as part of this project, I thought it'd be interesting
كجزء من هذا المشروع، اعتقدت أنه سيكون مثيراً للإهتمام
if she tried to meet someone.
إن حاولت ستاسي الخروج مع أحدهم.
So my idea was to have Stacey here go speed dating
كانت فكرتي أن تجرب ستاسي نظام التعارف السريع
in Las Vegas on Valentine's Day.
يوم عيد الحب في لاس فيغاس.
(Laughter) (Applause) (Music)
(ضحك) (تصفيق) (موسيقى)
SB: We ended up at what was advertised as the world's largest speed dating event.
ستايسي: انتهى بنا المطاف في ما أعلن أنه أكبر اجتماع للمواعدة السريعة.
I had 19 dates
حظيت بتسعة عشر موعداً.
and each date lasted three minutes.
واستمر كل منها لثلاث دقائق.
Participants were given a list of ice- breaker questions to get the ball rolling,
حصل كل مشارك على قائمة من الأسئلة لكسر الحاجز وتسهيل المحادثة.
things like, "If you could be any kind of animal, what would you be?"
أسئلة مثل: "إذا ما قدر أن تصبح حيواناً، فماذا تريد أن تكون؟"
That sort of thing.
هذا النوع من الأسئلة.
My first date was Colin.
كان موعدي الأول مع كولن.
He's from England,
هو من بريطانيا،
and he once married a woman he met after placing an ad for a Capricorn.
وكان متزوجاً من قبل من امرأة التقى بها بعد وضعه إعلاناً عن برج الجدي.
Alec and I saw him at the end of the evening,
رأيناه أنا وأليك في نهاية اليوم،
and he said he'd kissed a woman in line at one of the concession stands.
أخبرنا بأنه قبّل امرأة على منصة الامتياز.
Zack and Chris came to the date-a-thon together.
قدم زاك وكيس لهذا الحدث معاً.
This is Carl.
هذا كارل.
I asked Carl, "What's the first thing you notice about a woman?"
سألت كارل: "ما هو أول شيء تلاحظه على المرأة؟"
He said, "Tits."
أجابني: "حلمتي ثدييها."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Matthew is attracted to women with muscular calves.
ينجذب ماثيو للنساء اللواتي لديهن عضلات.
We talked about running. He does triathlons, I run half-marathons.
تحدثنا حول الركض، هو يشارك في سباق ثلاثي وأنا أجري نصف ماراثون.
Alec actually liked his eyes and asked if I was attracted to him, but I wasn't,
أعجب أليك بعينيه، فسألني إن كنت معحبة به ولكني لم أكن كذلك،
and I don't think he was attracted to me either.
ولا أعتقد أنه أعجب بي حتى.
Austin and Mike came together.
قدم أوستن ومايك معَا.
Mike asked me a hypothetical question.
طرح علي مايك سؤالا افتراضياً.
He said, "You're in an elevator running late for a meeting.
قال: "أنت في مصعد وقد تأخرت عن موعد الاجتماع.
Someone makes a dash for the elevator.
شخص ما يركض باتجاه المصعد.
Do you hold it open for them?"
هل ستوقفين المصعد من أجله؟"
And I said I would not.
فأجبته بأنني لن أفعل ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Cliff said the first thing he notices about a woman is her teeth,
أما كليف فقد أخبرني بأن أول شيء يلاحظه هو الأسنان.
and we complimented each other's teeth.
وأبدى كل منا إعجابه بأسنان الطرف الآخر.
Because he's an open mouth sleeper,
ولأنه ينام وفمه مفتوح،
he says he has to floss more to help prevent gum disease,
فقد قال لي بأنه يستعمل الخيط لمساعدته على منع أمراض اللثة
and so I asked him how often he flosses,
فسألته كم من مرة يستعملها في العادة،
and he said, "Every other day."
فأجابني،" كل يوم"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, as someone who flosses twice a day,
والان، وبالنسبة لشخص يستعمل الخيط مرتين في اليوم،
I wasn't really sure that that was flossing more
لم أكن متأكدة حقا أنه يستعمل الخيط أكثر من ذلك
but I don't think I said that out loud.
لكن لا أعتقد أنني قلت هذا بصوت مرتفع.
Bill is an auditor,
يعمل بيل كمدقق للحسابات،
and we talked the entire three minutes about auditing. (Laughter)
وتحدثنا حول عمله طيلة الدقائق الثلاث. (ضحك)
The first thing Spencer notices about a woman is her complexion.
أول شيء يلاحظه سبنسر في المرأة هو بشرتها.
He feels a lot of women wear too much makeup,
يعتقد أن العديد من النساء يضعن الكثير من مساحيق التجميل،
and that they should only wear enough to accentuate the features that they have.
في حين أنه يجب عليها فقط وضع القليل الكافي لإبراز جمالها.
I told him I didn't wear any makeup at all
أخبرته أنني لا أضع مساحيق التجميل أبداً.
and he seemed to think that that was a good thing.
فبدى عليه أنه يعتقد أن هذا أمر جيد.
Craig told me he didn't think I was willing to be vulnerable.
أخبرني كريغ أنه لا يعتقد أنني على استعداد لأكون عرضة للخطر.
He was also frustrated when I couldn't remember my most embarrassing moment.
كما أنه شعر بالأحباط عندما لم أتمكن من تذكر أكثر اللحظات الحرجة التي مررت بها.
He thought I was lying, but I wasn't.
إعتقد أنني أكذب لكنني لم أكن كذلك.
I didn't think he liked me at all, but at the end of the night,
أعتقد أنه لم يُعجب بي أبدًا ولكن في نهاية السهرة،
he came back to me and he gave me a box of chocolates.
عاد إليّ وقدّم لي علبة من الشوكولاتة.
William was really difficult to talk to.
كان من الصعب التحدث مع ويليام.
I think he was drunk.
أعتقد أنه كان في حالة سُكر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Actor Chris McKenna was the MC of the event.
كان الممثل كريس ماكينا هو من يدير هذا الحدث.
He used to be on "The Young and the Restless."
اعتاد أن يكون في برنامج "الشباب والاضطراب".
I didn't actually go on a date with him.
في الواقع لم أخرج في موعد معه.
Alec said he saw several women give their phone numbers to him.
أخبرني أليك أنه رأى بعض النساء يعطينه أرقام هواتفهن.
Needless to say, I didn't fall in love.
وبدون حاجة لأن أذكر ذلك، لم أقع في الحب.
I didn't feel a particular connection with any of the men that I went on dates with,
لم أشعر بأنه يوجد شيء يجذبني لأي واحد من الذين خرجت معهم،
and I didn't feel like they felt a particular connection with me either.
كما أنهم لم يشعروا بذلك أيضاً.
AS: Now, the most beautiful thing to me --
الآن، الشيء الجميل بالنسبة لي--
(Laughter) -- as a photographer is the quality of vulnerability.
(ضحك)--بالنسبة لي كمصور هو مدى التعرض للخطر.
The physical exterior reveals a crack in which you can get a glimpse
يكشف الشكل الخارجي عن صدع يمكنك من خلاله الحصول على لمحة
at a more fragile interior.
على داخله الهش.
At this date-a-thon event, I saw so many examples of that,
في هذا الحدث رأيت الكثير من هذه الأمثلة،
but as I watched Stacey's dates and talked to her about them,
ولكن بمراقبة الأشخاص الذين قابلتهم ستايسي والتحدث معها عنهم،
I realized how different photographic love is from real love.
أدركت مدى اختلاف الحب التصويري عن الحب الحقيقي.
What is real love? How does it work?
ما هو الحب الحقيقي؟ كيف يحدث؟
In order to work on this question and to figure out how someone goes
وبهدف الإجابة عن هذا السؤال ومعرفة كيف ينتقل الفرد من
from meeting on a date to having a life together,
مجرد الإلتقاء في موعد إلى العيش معاً،
Stacey and I went to Sun City Summerlin,
ذهبت برفقة ستايسي لمدينة سمرلين،
which is the largest retirement community in Las Vegas.
والتي تعتبر أكبر مجتمع من حيث عدد المتقاعدين في لاس فيغاس.
Our contact there was George, who runs the community's photography club.
كان جورج وسيلة اتصالنا هناك، كان يدير نادي التصوير الفوتفرافي للمجتمع.
He arranged for us to meet other couples in their makeshift photo studio.
قام بترتيب لقاءات مع الأزواج الآخرين في الأستديو المؤقت خاصتهم.
SB: After 45 years of marriage, Anastasia's husband died two years ago,
توفي زوج أنازتازيا منذ سنتين بعد زواج دام 45 سنة.
so we asked if she had an old wedding picture.
لذلك سألناها إن كانت تمتلك صورة قديمة لحفل زفافها.
She met her husband when she was a 15-year-old waitress
التقت بزوجها عندما كانت في الخامسة عشر من عمرها وتعمل كنادلة
at a small barbecue place in Michigan.
في محل للمشويات بميتشغن.
He was 30.
كان في الثلاثين من عمره.
She'd lied about her age.
هي كذبت بشأن عمرها.
He was the first person she'd dated.
كان أول شخص تخرج معه في موعد غرامي.
Dean had been named photographer of the year in Las Vegas two years in a row,
تم تسمية دين كمصور العام في لاس فيجاس لمرتين متتاليتين،
and this caught Alec's attention,
الشيئ الذي جذب انتباه أليك،
as did the fact that he met his wife, Judy,
كما أن حقيقة أنه التقى زوجته جودي،
at the same age when Alec met Rachel.
في نفس العمر الذي إلتقى فيه أليك بزوجته راشيل.
Dean admitted that he likes to look at beautiful women,
أقرّ دين بأنه يحب النظرإلى النساء الجميلات.
but he's never questioned his decision to marry Judy.
ولكنه لم يشكك في قراره بالزواج من جودي.
AS: George met Josephine at a parish dance.
أليك: التقى جورج بجوزفين في حلبة رقص.
He was 18, she was 15.
كان هو في الثامنة عشر وهي في الخامسة عشر.
Like a lot of the couples we met, they weren't especially philosophical
مثل الكثير من الأزواج الذين إلتقيناهم، لم يكونوا يعتمدون على فلسفة خاصة
about their early choices.
حول اختياراتهم المبكرة.
George said something that really stuck with me.
قال جورج شيئا علق في ذهني.
He said, "When you get that feeling, you just go with it."
قال:" عندما ينتابك ذلك الإحساس، فقط استسلم له."
Bob and Trudy met on a blind date when she was still in high school.
التقى بوب بتيدي في موعد غرامي حينما كانت لا تزال في الثانوية.
They said they weren't particularly attracted to each other
قالا أنهما لم يكونا فعلاً معجبين ببعضهم البعض
when the first met.
عند أول لقاء.
Nevertheless, they were married soon after.
ومع ذلك، تزوّجا بعد فترة وجيزة.
SB: The story that stayed with me the most
ستايسي: القصة التي بقيت عالقة في ذهني أكثر
was that of George, the photography club president, and his wife, Mary.
هي قصة جورج مدير نادي التصوير مع زوجته ماري.
This was George and Mary's second marriage.
كان هذا الزواج الثاني لكل من جورج وماري.
They met at a country-western club in Louisville, Kentucky called the Sahara.
التقيا في ناد يدعى الصحراء في لويزفيل بولاية كنتاكي.
He was there alone drinking and she was with friends.
كان وحيداً يشرب بينما هي مع أصدقائها.
When they started dating, he owed the IRS 9,000 dollars in taxes,
عندما بدأ يتقابلان، كان وقتها مديناَ لمصلحة الضرائب بمبلغ 9000 دولار
and she offered to help him get out of debt,
فعرضت عليه أن تساعده في التخلص من ديونه،
so for the next year, he turned his paychecks over to Mary,
فقام بتحويل راتبه لماري طيلة العام التالي،
and she got him out of debt.
وهي تكفلت بإخراجه من دينه.
George was actually an alcoholic when they married, and Mary knew it.
كانت ماري على علم بأن جورج مدمن كحول عندما تزّوجا،
At some point in their marriage, he says he consumed
في مرحلة ما من زواجهما، قال بأنه تناول
54 beers in one day.
54 قارورة جعة في يوم واحد.
Another time, when he was drunk, he threatened to kill Mary
وذات مرة، عندما كان في حالة سكر، هدد بقتل ماري،
and her two kids,
وطفليها،
but they escaped and a SWAT team was called to the house.
ولكنهم تمكنوا من الهرب، وتم استدعاء فرقة التدخل للمنزل.
Amazingly, Mary took him back,
بشكل مثير للدهشة، قبلت ماري بعودته مرة أخرى
and eventually things got better.
وفي نهاية الأمر تحسنت الأمور.
George has been involved in Alcoholics Anonymous
انضم جورج لبرنامج معالجة الإدمان الذي يعتمد على السرية.
and hasn't had a drink in 36 years.
ولم يتناول الخمر منذ 36 عاماً.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
At the end of the day, after we left Sun City,
وفي نهاية اليوم، بعد مغادرتنا المدينة،
I told Alec that I didn't actually think
أخبرت أليك أنني في الحقيقة لا أعتقد أن
that the stories of how these couples met were all that interesting.
قصص تقابل الأزواج كانت مشوقة.
What was more interesting
الشيء الأكثر تشويقا هو
was how they managed to stay together.
كيف تمكنوا من البقاء معاً.
AS: They all had this beautiful quality of endurance,
أليك: كانوا جميعاً يملكون هذه القدرة الرائعة على التحمل،
but that was true of the singles, too.
لكن كان هذا صحيحاً أيضاً بالنسبة للعزاب،
The world is hard, and the singles were out there
العالم صعب، يوجد الكثير من العزاب في الخارج
trying to connect with other people,
يحاولون التواصل مع الآخرين،
and the couples were holding onto each other
بينما الأزواج متمسكون ببعضهم البعض
after all these decades.
بعد كل هذه العقود.
My favorite pictures on this trip were of Joe and Roseanne.
تعتبر صورة جو وروزان من الصور المفضلة من هذه الرحلة،
Now, by the time we met Joe and Roseanne,
الان، ومنذ مقابلة جو وروزالين،
we'd gotten in the habit of asking couples if they had an old wedding photograph.
أصبحت لدينا عادة سؤال الأزواج إن كان لديهم صورة قديمة لزفافهم.
In their case, they simultaneously pulled out of their wallets
في حالتهم، يسحبان محفظتيهما في نفس الوقت
the exact same photograph.
عارضين نفس الصورة.
What's more beautiful, I thought to myself,
في قرارة نفسي، أتساءل إن كان الشيء الجميل هو
this image of a young couple who has just fallen in love
صورة زوجين شابين وقعا في الحب فقط
or the idea of these two people holding onto this image for decades?
أو فكرة أن هذين الشخصين تمسكا بهذه الصورة لعقود؟
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)